Anna E. Reynolds +371 28377278 eizenija@gmail.com Ģertrūdes iela 34-30 Rīga, LV-1011, LATVIA skype: reynoldsae

Current activities

Demokrātiskās izglītības institūts (Democratic Education Institute), co-founder An association founded in order to work with new paradigms in education in the form of presentations, workshops, and teacher training modules.

Radošā rakstu darbnīca (Wonderful Word Workshop) LLC, owner This is my newly established business platform for the translation, copywriting, and editing work I have been doing for almost two decades.

Work history

2001 - present: Freelance translator, translating academic, cultural, and advertising texts from Latvian to English

2011-2012: Jaunpiebalgas Tautskola, English teacher, adult classes in the Latvian countryside

2006-2008: *Mozaīka*, Alliance of LGBT and their Friends, Office Manager, responsible for all office procedures including EU & LV projects, successful collaboration with Amnesty International.

2003 -2006: International School of Riga, Main Administrator; admissions; created administrative procedures; participated in the successful preparation of the school for accreditation; managed the school's website; responsible for advertising.

2001-2003: Latvian country school *99 Baltie Zirgi*: taught English at various levels from K-7; organized adult education courses; taught Active ParentingTM courses, solved administrative questions.

2000-2003: Eiženija Enterprises: created a small business in Sweden in order to do translation work and teach Active Parenting™ courses.

1998-2001: www.ParentNetSweden.com, non-profit website for English speaking parents in Sweden, participated in the foundation of the website.

1994-1997: Freelance translator, translated academic and commercial material from Swedish to English.

Education

2010-11:	University of Latvia Riga, Latvia: Anthropology
1992–93:	University of Washington Seattle, WA: Russian Language and
	Literature BA
1990–91:	Reed College Portland, OR: History
1989–90:	Jozsef Attila Tudomanyegyetem, Szeged, Hungary: Hungarian
	Language & Linguistics
1988–89:	University of Oregon Eugene, OR: Russian
1986–88:	Reed College Portland, OR: Russian and Music

Certificates

2012: Toastmasters

2007: Human Rights Education Associates Project Development and Management

in the NGO sector-Certificate

2006: Human Rights Documentation and Advocacy in Bucharest, Romania— Certificate

2005: MS Access Level 1 course—Certificate 2005: Latvian Office procedures—Certificate

1999: Active Parenting in Sweden: Child psychology

Languages

English native, Latvian very good, Swedish very good, Russian conversational, German conversational

Publications

www.theBalticTravel.eu Destination Management Company for Lithuania, Latvia and Estonia, 2009. Website Anna Reynolds, Text

Comparative Baltic Literature series: *Back to Baltic Memory: Lost and Found in Literature:* 1940-1968 University of Latvia, Institute of Literature, Folklore, and Art 2008, Editors Eva Eglāja Ķirsone and Benedikts Kalnačs. English editor, Anna Reynolds

Comparative Baltic Literature series: *Latvieši, Igauņi un Lietuvieši: Literārie un kultūras kontakti* University of Latvia, Institute of Literature, Folklore, and Art 2008, Editors Benedikts Kalnačs et al. Translations to English, Anna Reynolds

collegium litterarum 21 We Have Something in Common: The Baltic Memory Editors Anneli Mihkelvi and Benedikts Kalnačs, The Under and Tuglas Literature Centre of the Estonian Academy of Sciences and the institute of Literature, Folklore and Art of the University of Latvia, 2007. English editor, Anna Reynolds

Acta Ibseniana IV *Ibsen Reception in Poland and the Baltic Nations*, Editors Knut Brynhildsvoll, Lech Sokól and Benedikts Kalnačs, Centre for Ibsen Studies, University of Oslo, 2006. English editor, Anna Reynolds

References

Aija Lulle, University of Latvia, Department of Anthropology, Lecturer, + 371 29152006, aija.lulle@lu.lv

Valentīna Dolmane, Jaunpiebalgas Tautskola, Director, +371 29146397, tautskola@jaunpiebalga.lv



My favourite photo from Christmas 2012. Me and my puppies.